VISHAL CHANDRA CHAPA

Junior Fullstack Software Developer

Github: https://github.com/Vishalchapa/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vishal-chandra-chapa-1548871ab//
Portfolio: https://vishalchapa.github.io/Portfolio/
Manchester/vishc264@gmail.com/+447435378497

Executive Summary

I am a Junior Software Developer specialized in Full Stack Development, Support Engineering, and Data Science. I bring a blend of technical expertise and strategic vision to my work. I am a certified Frontend Developer, with Level-3 certification in Data Science and Level-2 certification by NCFE. My strong interpersonal and leadership skills complement my technical abilities, positioning me as an ideal candidate for your organization. With experience in software analysis, maintenance, and management, I hold both MSc and Bachelor degrees.

Education

June 2024 - Present

Code Institute

Dublin, Ireland (Remote)

Diploma in FullStack Software Development (Accredited by the University West of Scotland)

Sept 2021 - Jun 2023

Anglia Ruskin University Cambridge, United Kingdom

Master of Science - International Business

Technical Skillset

Technologies	Databases	Frameworks	Version Control
HTML CSS Javascript Python	MongoDB MySQL	Django jQuery Bootstrap	Git Github

Portfolio Projects

- 1. Love Running I developed the Scope, Structure, Skeleton, and Surface Planes in User Experience Essentials, completed the Love Running Walkthrough Project with completion of Code Validation and Manual Testing, and dove into core CSS & Grid System. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS. Link to live deployed site: https://vishalchapa.github.io/love-running/
- 2. CaskDrop I built on my Bootstrap knowledge with components and created the structure for my CaskDrop Website and Personal Portfolio with completion of Code Validation and Manual Testing. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS & Bootstrap. Link to live deployed site: https://vishalchapa.github.io/CaskDrop/
- 3. **Portfolio** Personal Portfolio Project, ensured it's optimised for mobile devices, tablets, and desktops. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS & Bootstrap. Link to live deployed site: https://vishalchapa.github.io/Portfolio/

Collaborative Projects

Hackathon - The hackathon spanned three days, Our team developed "The Art of Tea," a three-page website that immerses users in the rich history and culture of tea from China, Japan, and India. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS & Bootstrap. Link to live deployed site: https://cloud-monkey.github.io/Hackathon1-theartoftea/

Work Experience

Feb 2024 - May 2024 GAO Tek Inc Support Engineer Remote(UK)

- Worked as a Support Engineer delivering exceptional user interface support by promptly addressing user queries and technical issues.
- This involves troubleshooting UI-related solutions, providing clear and concise instructions, and ensuring seamless user experiences. Collaborating with senior developers and UX/UI designers with expertising in wordpress.
- Overall, with GAO Tek Inc, I have contributed UI functionality, Team- Collaboration, Documentation,
 Analysing and Project Management.

May 2022 - Jan 2024 Best One Express Manager Cambridge

- I have identified potential new clients and markets, improved service for existing customers through analysing.
- I also managed risks, train, Hire and mentor team members.

Sep 2022 -Mar 2023 Orcalo Data Analyst Intern Remote(UK)

- I am Responsible for developing, decoded and encoded software web applications.
- Maintained and keeping up to date with data systems, collaborated with multiple teams to identified process improvements and develop strategies.
- Utilised statistical tools for data analysis, generated reports for management and propose system analysis to enhance user-reach.

Certificates/Courses

- LinkedIn Essential HTML (15 hours)
- IT Talent Hub Full Stack (3 Months)
- Level 2 Understanding Coding (1 Month)
- Responsive Web Design at freeCodeCamp (3 days)
- Data Science with Board Infinity (3 Months)

Additional Information/Interests

- I am currently working on building my ReactJS projects.
- Regular engagement on Slack tech forum.
- I attend Coding Community meetups in Leeds.
- Fluent English/Hindi

References available on request.